<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-15T18:53:15+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Brad Kwon</title><subtitle>Brad Kwon's site</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Xamarin Android Emulator Setup in Visual Studio 2017</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/2017/11/15/xamarin-setup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Xamarin Android Emulator Setup in Visual Studio 2017" /><published>2017-11-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/2017/11/15/xamarin-setup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/2017/11/15/xamarin-setup/">&lt;p&gt;
I've recently started to learn Xamarin to build any mobile app with C# because I've mainly used C# for programming. 
The concept of Xamarin which is write-once, run everywhere seemed quite attractive so I decided to learn it.  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
What I had to do at first is to set up Xamarin development environment. 
I chose a Visual Studio 2017 community version. 
For iOS deployment, I have to use either an iMac or a Macbook. 
As I only have Windows environment, so I decided to go with android first and try out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xamarin.com/live&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Xamarin Live Player&lt;/a&gt; app for iOS deployment. 
The live player function enables developers to deploy iOS apps to their actual iPhones via the live player app.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To install the Visual Studio 2017 was easy as well as Xamarin development tools. 
I could choose whatever tools I want to install on the workload while installing.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;popupImg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://developer.xamarin.com/guides/cross-platform/troubleshooting/questions/visualstudio-2017-rc/Images/install1-orig.png&quot; alt=&quot;Visual Studio Installer Workloads View&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Visual Studio Installer Workloads View&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The problem was when I tried to deploy an Android project to an emulator. 
I found out that there are two types of emulators. One is using Android SDK and another is using Visual Studio Emulator for Android. 
After taking a closer look on them, I found out that Visual Studio Emulator for Android is much faster than Android SDK 
so I installed it through Visual Studio installer again. 
You can select it to install in the Individual components &amp;gt; Emulators menu.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;popupImg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://social.msdn.microsoft.com/Forums/getfile/1012756&quot; alt=&quot;Visual Studio Installer Individual components View&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Choose Visual Studio Emulator for Android under Emulators if it is not selected.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I installed that emulator on my computer and tried to deploy again. 
But this time, I couldn’t see anything running on the emulator although everything looked fine.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;popupImg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/tech/img/20171115/xamarin-android-emulator-setup1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Debugging running view&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Everything seems fine.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
So I googled what went wrong and finally reached this page.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.xamarin.com/discussion/62307/xamarin-android-projects-failed-to-deploy-in-visual-studio-emulator-for-android&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://forums.xamarin.com/discussion/62307/xamarin-android-projects-failed-to-deploy-in-visual-studio-emulator-for-android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My case came under both the CPU compatibility and the registry.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My CPU was Intel i7-6600U and its code name is SkyLake and this CPU has an issue with Hyper-V that the Visual Studio Emulator for Android depends on. In order to sort this out, I followed this step.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Open the Hyper-V Manager and go to settings of the virtual device.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;popupImg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/tech/img/20171115/xamarin-android-emulator-setup2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hyper-V Manager main view&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Right-click on the emulator you want to set up and choose settings.&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Check off “Migrate to a physical computer with a different processor version” in the Processor &amp;gt; Compatibility menu.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;popupImg&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/tech/img/20171115/xamarin-android-emulator-setup3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hyper-V Manager processor compatibility configuration view&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Secondly, for the registry for Android SDK Tools path, I created a new “Android SDK Tools” key under &lt;blockquote&gt;HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\WOW6432Node\&lt;/blockquote&gt; because there wasn’t existing key like others. Then I added a string value with “Path” for name and the Android SDK full path on my computer for data. 
I could get the Android SDK full path from &lt;blockquote&gt;Visual Studio &amp;gt; Tools &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Xamarin &amp;gt; Android Settings &amp;gt; Android SDK Location&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;popupImg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/tech/img/20171115/xamarin-android-emulator-setup4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visual Studio tools options view&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Copy and paste it to the registry.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Eventually, I could see something different on the output window after executing debugging.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;popupImg&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/tech/img/20171115/xamarin-android-emulator-setup5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visual Studio tools options view&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Deployment Success!!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Happy Coding!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I've recently started to learn Xamarin to build any mobile app with C# because I've mainly used C# for programming. The concept of Xamarin which is write-once, run everywhere seemed quite attractive so I decided to learn it. What I had to do at first is to set up Xamarin development environment. I chose a Visual Studio 2017 community version. For iOS deployment, I have to use either an iMac or a Macbook. As I only have Windows environment, so I decided to go with android first and try out the Xamarin Live Player app for iOS deployment. The live player function enables developers to deploy iOS apps to their actual iPhones via the live player app. To install the Visual Studio 2017 was easy as well as Xamarin development tools. I could choose whatever tools I want to install on the workload while installing. Visual Studio Installer Workloads View The problem was when I tried to deploy an Android project to an emulator. I found out that there are two types of emulators. One is using Android SDK and another is using Visual Studio Emulator for Android. After taking a closer look on them, I found out that Visual Studio Emulator for Android is much faster than Android SDK so I installed it through Visual Studio installer again. You can select it to install in the Individual components &amp;gt; Emulators menu. Choose Visual Studio Emulator for Android under Emulators if it is not selected. I installed that emulator on my computer and tried to deploy again. But this time, I couldn’t see anything running on the emulator although everything looked fine. Everything seems fine. So I googled what went wrong and finally reached this page. https://forums.xamarin.com/discussion/62307/xamarin-android-projects-failed-to-deploy-in-visual-studio-emulator-for-android My case came under both the CPU compatibility and the registry. My CPU was Intel i7-6600U and its code name is SkyLake and this CPU has an issue with Hyper-V that the Visual Studio Emulator for Android depends on. In order to sort this out, I followed this step. Open the Hyper-V Manager and go to settings of the virtual device. Right-click on the emulator you want to set up and choose settings. Check off “Migrate to a physical computer with a different processor version” in the Processor &amp;gt; Compatibility menu. Secondly, for the registry for Android SDK Tools path, I created a new “Android SDK Tools” key under HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\WOW6432Node\ because there wasn’t existing key like others. Then I added a string value with “Path” for name and the Android SDK full path on my computer for data. I could get the Android SDK full path from Visual Studio &amp;gt; Tools &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Xamarin &amp;gt; Android Settings &amp;gt; Android SDK Location Copy and paste it to the registry. Eventually, I could see something different on the output window after executing debugging. Deployment Success!! Happy Coding!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coming Soon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/11/07/coming-soon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming Soon" /><published>2017-11-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-11-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/11/07/coming-soon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/11/07/coming-soon/">&lt;p&gt;Coming soon..&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Coming soon..</summary></entry></feed>